SALVATORE **TRUPIANO**





PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a driven student at Oakland University, studying to obtain a Bachelor of Science degree in the field of Information Technology. I have five years of professional IT experience and am looking for new opportunities to expand and contribute my knowledge in this field. The skills I bring to the workplace are not only technical, but also a wide range of soft skills including excellent verbal and written communication, patience, commitment, and organization. For a complete listing of projects I have completed, please see my LinkedIn page.



EDUCATION

B.S. Information Technology | Oakland University | Junior Status

September 2017 – Present

Cumulative GPA (as of Winter 2020): 3.97

Relevant Completed/Ongoing Coursework: Software Engineering and Practice, System Administration, Database Design and Implementation, Introduction to Computer Networking, System Administration, Introduction to Computer Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Interactive Web Development

High School Diploma | Bishop Foley Catholic High School August 2013 – May 2017



EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Support Specialist | Bishop Foley Catholic High School July 2014 – Present

Responsibilities include, but are not limited to:

- Assisting IT director in providing Technical Support to 45+ Staff Members and 300+ Students.
- Setting-up and maintaining teacher/student workstations.
- Prepping, imaging, and deploying Chromebook computers up to 200 per cycle.
- Prepping, imaging, and deploying staff and student computers.
- Installation of new systems including wiring, initial setup, and technical training (if applicable)
- Organization and inventory tracking of central server room.
- Assisting IT Director in purchasing new PCs, Chromebooks, projectors, printers, monitors, audio/visual equipment, etc.
- Monitoring and diagnosing network errors and problems (Wired + Wireless).
- Assisting IT Director in Windows Server troubleshooting.
- Providing Audio/Visual service and technical support for all events.
- Adapt to, learn, and implement new technologies quickly and effectively.

Information Technology Consultant | Freelance

September 2018 – Present

Providing technical support and advising for small businesses and individuals in the following areas:

- Supporting Windows, MacOS workstations
- Research and advising for purchasing and upgrading computer hardware and software
- Supporting various softwares such as: MS Office, MS Exchange, QuickBooks, Fishbowl, and VPN clients such as Pulse Secure.
- Website development and maintenance
- Technology-based Advertising and Marketing (SEO, Social Media, Video Editing with Premiere CC, and logo/photo editing with Photoshop CC)

Technology Coordinator | Guardian Angels Catholic Church & School September 2018 – October 2019

Responsibilities Include:

- Meeting with administrative staff and setting priorities, budget, and technology plan for the current year
- Set up and maintenance of teacher/student workstations as well as computer peripherals
- Prepping, imaging, and deploying Google Chromebook laptops, up to 50 per year
- Maintaining and implementing new projectors, printers, and other peripherals into classrooms.
- Research and purchasing new servers, PCs, Chromebooks, projectors, printers, monitors, and audio/visual equipment, and software from various vendors
- Maintaining Windows Server and Ubiquiti/Cisco Meraki network infrastructure
- Technical Support of up to 40 Staff Members.



SKILLS

- Proficiency in Windows OS set up, maintenance, and troubleshooting
- Proficient in the Microsoft Office Suite
- High Proficiency in Cisco Meraki MX security appliance interface, operation, and troubleshooting
- Moderate proficiency in Printer/Scanner setup and maintenance
- Knowledge and proficiency in various aspects of networking (DNS, DHCP, Layer-3 and 7 firewall, IP protocol, and networking devices such as access points, switches, and modems)
- Experienced in researching, evaluating, and purchasing new technology hardware and software
- Custom image deployment using Windows Deployment Services

- Demonstrated proficiency with G-Suite Administrator interface & Chromebook Device management
- G-Suite Client interfaces (G-Mail, Google Docs, Drive, Sheets, and Slides)
- Moderate proficiency with Windows Server administration of Active Directory, DNS, WDS, File, and Print sharing
- Web Frameworks: HTML, CSS, PHP
- Python & Bash programming languages
- Advanced knowledge of live production A/V equipment
- Advanced knowledge of and proficient in suite of Ubiquiti UniFi networking products.